<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
	<articles>
		<article>
			<title>The relationship between Circle Walking and Zhan Zhuang</title>
			<body>
				Circle walking is the logical progression from Zhan Zhuang. In Zhan Zhuang, one seeks movement in stillness. In Circle Walking, one seeks stillness in movement. Both practices exist in a mutually beneficial relationship.
			
				When one holds a given posture for a prolonged duration, the body develops a visceral image of the standing shape. It can be said that this image is painted on the muscles, fascia and tendons of the body. Slowly but surely and once one is able to relax into ones structure, one begins to be conscious of the myriad of movements which occur within the body. Oftentimes, we are so concerned with what is going on outside of our body that we fail to notice the changes and movements within.
				
				In Circle Walking, one employs the structural integrity learnt in Zhan Zhuang in movement. As one walks around the centre of the circle, periodically changing direction, the postural rootedness of Zhan Zhuang is maintained. As the world spins around us and constantly changes, we are able to remain grounded in the moment, composed and an balanced. This is truly a deep art.
			</body>
		</article>
		<article>
			<title>The 8 guiding principles of Bagua Zhang</title>
			<body>
				1. UPHOLDING: The tongue tip presses to the top of the mouth. The essences, chi and spirit are upheld to the Bahui (Crown chakra) point.
				2. UPRIGHT: The head, body and heart must be upright.
				3. THE 3 POINTS: The tip of the hand, foot and nose must point in the same direction.
				4. THE 4 EXTREMITIES: Strength must be contained in the extremities of bone, blood, tendons and flesh. The tongue is the extremity of the flesh, teeth of bone, hair of blood, nails of tendon. One must be able to put strength into all of these.
				5. THE 5 UNIQUE ASPECTS: When moving, the 5 major joints must be rounded to allow for their unique uses to be manifest. These are the shoulders, elbows, wrists, waist and knees.
				6. THE 6 HARMONIES: The eyes and the heart/mind must be unified. Where you look is where your thought must be. You must be focussed.. The waist and body must be unified. Wherever the body turns, the waist must also turn. The hands and the feet must be unified. If the foot points forward, the hand must point in the same direction.
				7. THE 7 STARS: This refers to 7 star stepping. This is the basis of changing footwork. It also refers to the 7 styles of attacking when moving on the circle.
				8. THE 8 TRIGRAMS: There are 4 Yang (Chien, Kan, Gun and Jun) and 4 Yin trigrams (Xun, Li, Kun, and Dui). The functions of Chi for humans are 	opening, closing, gathering, dispersing, raising, lowering, exiting and entering. All movements affect the 8 functions of chi.		
			</body>
		</article>
		<article>
			<title>
				Circle Walking as a meditative practice
			</title>
			<body>
				Circle walking is derived from Daoist Chi cultivation and meditative practices. The Daoists of the Long Men sect were concerned with a union of Man, Heaven, and Earth and thus surmised that if one was able to meditate whilst in sustained movement, one could effectively merge with the patterns of nature, absorbing the Chi of Heaven and Earth. As nothing in nature stands perfectly still, persistent motion while meditating is more natural. Whereas Buddhist meditation is static and inwardly focussed, the Daoist circle walking practice is a moving meditation with the intention focused outward. In this practice, the practitioner seeks to merge with the natural world.
			
				When walking the circle with a meditative focus, the pace needs to be fluid and steady. The walking speed should be slow to moderate and the step itself should be continuous and natural. Bend the knees and sink the waist slightly so as to aid in the sinking of the Chi to the Dantian. If the body sways unnaturally, bobbing up and down, the Chi will be unsettled and not sink. Upon the sinking of the Chi to the Dantian, the body feels comfortably rooted and is more easily able to maintain a meditative state.
				
				When walking, the practitioner should keep their focus on the tip of the leading finger. Much like Hastagrahe Drishti, the fingertips of the leading hand provide one with a focal point for the gaze, providing one with the means to develop concentrated intention. The breathing must be smooth and relaxed and the practitioner may choose to repeat a mantra. This does not need to be of religious significance and can be as simple as repeating the number of circles one has turned. Typically a practitioner will circle in one direction for a desired number of rotations and then switch directions and walk in the other direction for the same number of rotations.
			</body>
		</article>
		<article>
			<title>Zhan Zhuang</title>
			<body>
				Zhan Zhuang or Stake Standing is a very powerful standing Chi Gung / postural meditation which both builds and strengthens ones internal energy. Dedicated practice of this method will build up a structure (posture) in our body from which whole body force can be produced and ultimately released.
			
				Although deceptively simple on the outside, Zhan Zhuang is a deeply profound practice. In all standing exercises, we strive to use the mind to move energy within our body. Initially one performs basic visualisations such as holding a ball and feeling it's expansion and contraction. Within time, you will actually be able to feel these sensations as the mind (Yi) acts on the energy (Chi) to create internal energy (Jing or Shen). At the beginning these sensations are quite tangible and include feelings of tingling, heaviness, expansion and warmth. As the body slowly opens and composure appears, the grosser sensations vanish and the movement of the finer energies becomes possible.
					
				Stand still, quiet and tall. Keep your head up and look forward, ensuring that your crown is lifted. Your eyes should be open, with a soft and wide angled focus. Gently raise your arms until your hands are in front of your chest with your elbows bent and hands facing the body. Leave some space between the bicep and side of chest and ensure that your fingers are soft, rounded and spread. Bend your knees slightly so as to maintain your balance. Look forward, keeping your gaze level and alert. Try to be present in the moment, observing and letting go of physical sensations and thoughts whenever they arise.
			</body>
		</article>
		<article>
			<title>10 important points about Circle Walking</title>
			<body>
				1. HEAD: The head must be kept erect when walking. Slightly draw in the chin and naturally let the head extend upwards. Endeavour to look straight ahead when walking the circle and do not twist your neck. Rather, let the twist of your waist bring your focus to the circle's centre. With the head looking straight ahead, the spirit will be focused and the mind concentrated. Ensure that you breathe through your nose when practicing, inhaling deepy into the lower abdomen. Gently close your mouth without clenching the teeth and press your tongue to the upper palate. This results in saliva being produced. This saliva is called 'Golden Saliva and Jade Fluid' by the Taoists and 'Amrit' in Yogic science. It has manifold health benefits.

				2. BACK: Both shoulders should move slightly forward to round the back. When the back has been rounded, the chest will naturally move slighty inwards, allowing strength to pass to the front of the body. It must be noted that one should not move the shoulders forward with too much strength. This will only result in the back becoming tense. Simply relax the chest so that the upper part of the body feels naturally stretched. This facilitates the sinking of Chi to the Dantian.

				3. SHOULDERS: Both shoulders should move forward and simultaneously relax and drop. Relaxed and dropped shoulders help the diaphragm to drop. This naturally leads to a sensation of a sunken lower body and a solid but relaxed upper body.

				4. ARMS: The front wrist is level, upright, square and straight. The palm is facing up. The palm and forearm turn to the outside and stab forward. The upper arm folds back in, with a slight pulling back in away from the direction in which the forearm stabs. The lead elbow is above the heel of the lead foot. Relax the shoulder and drop the elbow. The angle between the upper and lower sections of the lead arm is about 150 degrees. The rear wrist hooks down, the rear palm is facing down. The palm and forearm wrap back in and stab forward. The upper arm turns out to the outside with a pulling back and away force.

				5. ELBOWS:When the shoulders sink and the elbows drop, strength is able to freely move to the hands.

				6. HANDS: The four fingers of each hand are held together, with the thumb tucked in towards the Laogong point. The four fingers contain a feeling a stabbing.

				7. WAIST: The waist should be agile and smoothly turn like an axle. When walking, it should feel as if you are sitting into your waist. This will enable the turns of the body to be flexible, agile and powerful.

				8. BUTTOCKS: The tongue should touch the upper palate and simultaneously, the perineum should be lifted, hips drawn in and the buttocks smoothed. This is the 'bridge' for connecting and opening what is know as the Ren and Du meridians in Traditional Chinese medicine or Ida and Pingala in Yogic theory. If Chi can sink into Dantian and the Ren and Du meridians are opened, then Dantian power can be used in the expression of force.

				9. THIGHS: The rear leg must support the whole body while the front leg leads. The hips drive the knees and the knees drive the feet to move forward. When the knees close, the crotch is covered and protected.

				10. FEET: When walking the circle the inner foot steps in a straight line and the outer one toes-in slightly to the center of the circle. Only in this way will one walk along a circle. One should slightly rub the inner ankle of the front leg with the rear foot and feet should not move higher than about one inch above the ground. Every step is a kick and every kick is a step.
			</body>
		</article>						
	</articles>